ENG SHILE

LANGUAGES

English

Proficient



SKILLS

Language

JavaScript · TypeScript · Python · PHP

Front End

HTML · CSS · SASS · Bootstrap ·

Tailwind · MUI · Styled-components ·

React · Redux · Next.js · React Hooks ·

React Context · Redux Persist ·

React Query · React Table

Back End

Node.js · Express · Django · NestJS ·

Laravel · GraphQL · RESTful API ·

tRPC · Flask · Java · C#

UI Design

UX/UI · Figma · Sketch · Zeplin

Database

MongoDB · MySQL · PostgreSQL ·

Sqlite · Supabase · Firebase · HBase ·

Airtable

Testing Approach & Frameworks

TDD · Jest · ESlint · Cypress ·

PHPUnit · PyTest

Cloud Framework / **Technologies**

Docker · AWS ·

Google Cloud Platform · Azure

React Full Stack Developer

- +60 1153361470 @ alberteng0825@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/albert-eng-b85671294
- Jalan Mewah Ria 4/7, Johor Bahru, Johor 81200, Malaysia

SUMMARY

I am an experienced full-stack web developer with over 5 years of experience handling all aspects of the development process for high-scale web and mobile applications. My proficiency in diverse industries such as Blockchain, E-commerce, Healthcare, and Education has allowed me to understand my clients' business needs successfully. I have built and managed secure websites and possess comprehensive knowledge of

My expertise includes working with Linux command line tools, and I pride myself on writing clean, well-tested, and well-documented code.

In addition to this, I have successfully completed projects with tight deadlines in highstress environments. As a result, I am resourceful, self-motivated, and proactive in ensuring project success.

With a pragmatic approach, I handle the front-end to back-end tasks, including hosting, site design, and system administration.

I do not shy away from responsibilities and never use phrases like "That's not my job." Throughout my career, I have collaborated with multi-functional teams and have been successful in delivering 40+ projects.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering

2014 - 2018

Central Carolina Technical College

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

04/2023 - Present

Upwork

Location Handled several text and image processing tasks based on Python and Django

- Managed tens of clients living in different timezones
- Provided clear updates and keeping the tight deadlines
- Provided 100% work success rate
- Developed several Solana game projects such as roulette and spin wheels

React Front End Developer (Remote, Contract)

10/2022 - 04/2023

Mad Dog Car Club

USA

- Developed the front end of 3 projects using React, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Material-UI, TypeScript, Next.js, React Hooks, Context API, and Styled-components
- Integrated web3 parts into Ethereum, Solana and Cardano projects using web3.js and ethers.js
- Resolved image optimization and utilized a cookie parser to improve the performance of page loading by 240%
- Transformed the user experience by incorporating lazy loading via a streamlined and effective paginated API.
- Resulted in a 60% improvement in page loading speed and substantial decrease in bounce rates
- Collaborated closely with the designer and backend developer, maintaining good teamwork through communication channels such as Slack, Trello, and weekly scrum meetinas

SKILLS

Hosting & Domain service

cPanel · Namecheap · Ionos · Vercel ·

Netlify · Heroku · Railway · Hostinger

ΑI

OpenAl · Dalle Model · Tensorflow · Deep Learning · Keras · Whisper

Project Management Tool Jira · Trello · Asana · Zoho · Clickup

EXPERIENCE

React Full Stack Developer (Remote, Contract)

03/2022 - 10/2022

AutoScribe

USA Oversaw the entire development process from start to finish using React, Django,

- AWS for 2 months Crafted and executed an MFA user authentication system that uplifted security by 50%, flawlessly integrated payment processing, resulting in a revenue jump of 30%, and pioneered AI audio processing
- 2 Mobile app development using React Native, Expo UI, Laravel, Node.js, Firebase, Supabase
- To ensure scalability, used a cloud-based hosting solution and implemented load balancing to distribute traffic across multiple servers.
- Optimized the website's performance by implementing caching, minimizing page load times, and optimizing images and other media files
- Revamped website traffic and user experience by 37%

Full Stack Blockchain Engineer (Remote, Full-time)

03/2020 - 03/2022

Taiwan

Bitfinex

Created and optimized components using React and Next.js. Cut development speed by 9%

- Drove best practice implementation for 22 employees across multiple departments. Decreased rework by 23% and costs by 15%
- Introduced effective database caching schema. Improved database access rate by
- Structured REST-based web services and serverless backend. Increased the user interaction by 30%
- Enhanced the Software Quality 15% by fixing the 150 bugs using React, Next.js, Express, Django, Laravel, AWS, Docker, Java, .NET
- Developed and launched 2 DeFi projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Web3.js and Smart contracts

Full Stack Developer (Hybrid Remote, Full-Time)

12/2018 - 02/2020

Resonac Hard Disk Singapore Pte Ltd

SG

- Played a key role in the development, improvement, and operation of 7 web-based software using React
- Gained hands-on expertise in Node, Express, Nest, Django and other back-end frameworks as well as front-end frameworks and library such as React and Next.js
- Involved in new mock-ups and UI specifications for holiday events and raised 25% more in total sale leads
- Upgraded an ecommerce web apps to sell products online using Laravel and Wordpress. Expanded company revenue by 58%